In this video, we're going to begin a discussion of Register Allocation which is
在本视频中，我们将开始讨论寄存器分配
one of the most sophisticated things that compilers do to optimize performance and
编译器做的最复杂的事情之一是优化性能和
also involves many of the concepts that we've been discussing in global flow
还涉及我们在全球流程中讨论的许多概念
analysis. Recall that intermediate code can use unlimited numbers of temporaries
分析。回想一下，中间代码可以使用无限数量的临时
and this simplifies a number of things. Particularly it simplifies optimization so
这简化了很多事情。特别是它简化了优化，因此
we don't have to worry about preserving the right number of registers in the code.
我们不必担心在代码中保留正确数量的寄存器。
But, it does complicate the final translation into assembly code cuz we
但是，它确实使最终翻译成汇编代码变得复杂，因为我们
might be using too many temporaries and this is actually a problem in practice.
可能使用了太多的临时语句，这在实践中实际上是一个问题。
So, it's not uncommon at all for intermediate code to use more temporaries
因此，中间代码使用更多临时代码并不少见
than there are registers on the target machine. The problem then is to rewrite
比目标机器上的寄存器多。那么问题就是重写
the intermediate code to use no more temporaries than there are machine
中间代码使用的临时代码不比机器多
registers and the way we're going to do that is we're going to assign multiple
寄存器，我们要做的是将多个
temporaries to each register. So, we're going to have a many-one mapping. A many
每个登记处都有临时工。所以，我们将会有一个多-一映射。很多人
to one mapping from temporaries to registers, okay? And, clearly there's a
一个从临时到寄存器的映射，好吗？而且，很明显有一个
little bit of an issue here if we really are using many temporaries, we will not be
这里有一个小问题，如果我们真的使用了很多临时函数，我们就不会
able to fit them all into a single register. So there needs to be some kind
能够将它们全部放入一个寄存器中。所以一定要有某种
of a trick and we'll say what that trick is in a few minutes and there will be
几分钟后我们会说出那是什么把戏
situations actually when this will fail, we'll have to have some kind of back up
实际情况当这将失败时，我们将不得不有某种形式的支持
plan. But our default plan is to try to put as many temporaries as possible into
计划一下。但我们的默认计划是尝试把尽可能多的临时人员
the same machine register. And doing all of this without changing the behavior of
相同的机器寄存器。在不改变行为的情况下完成所有这些操作
the program. So, how can we do this? Magic thing. How can we actually make a single
这个项目。那么，我们怎么才能做到这一点呢？神奇的东西。我们怎么才能真正让一首单曲
register hold multiple values? Well, the trick is that it's fine for registers to
寄存器是否包含多个值？嗯，诀窍是登记员可以
have local values as long as it only has one value at a time. So, let's consider
只要一次只有一个值，就具有本地值。那么，让我们考虑一下
this program, I'm going to switch colors here. Okay. Simple three statement program
这个程序，我要在这里切换颜色。好吧。简单的三语句程序
and notice here that a is used in the first two statements. So it's written in
注意，这里在前两个语句中使用了a。所以它是写在
the first statement, read in the second stateme nt e is written in the second
在第二个状态中读取的第一个语句写入第二个状态
statement and read in the third statement and that is only written in the third
语句，并在第三个语句中读取，并且只在第三个语句中写入
statement. And actually, these three values a, e and f, they don't ever really
声明。实际上，这三个值a，e和f，
co-exist at the same time but at the time we've read a we are really done with it.
在同一时间共存，但当我们读完一本书的时候，我们真的受够了。
We've all the uses that they are going to have in this little code fragment. Here,
我们拥有它们将在这个小代码片段中使用的所有用途。这里,
I'm assuming that a and effort are not used anywhere else and so it turns out
我假设a和努力没有在其他地方使用，所以结果是
that a, e, and f could all actually live in the same register. Alright, that's
a，e和f实际上都可以位于同一个寄存器中。好的，那就是
assuming that a and e are dead after their uses. And what will that look like, well
假设a和e在使用后死亡。那会是什么样子呢，嗯
let's allocate them all to a particular register r1 and let's assign c, d, and b
让我们将它们全部分配给特定的寄存器R1，并将c、d和b
into their own individual registers and the code would like this, r1 would be r2 +
放入它们自己的单独寄存器中，代码如下所示，R1将是R2+
r3, and then r1 would be r1 + r4 and r1 would be r1 - one. And so now notice how
R3，那么R1将是R1+R4，R1将是R1-1。所以现在请注意如何
this is just a transliteration of the code over here into registers but there is a
这只是将这里的代码音译到寄存器中，但是有一个
many one mapping of names on the left to register names on the right. A register
左侧的多个名称映射到右侧的注册名称。收银机
allocation is an old problem. In fact, it was first recognized way back in the 1950s
分配是一个老问题。事实上，早在20世纪50年代，人们就已经认识到这一点。
in the original Fortran project but originally, register allocation was done
在最初的Fortran项目中，但最初是进行寄存器分配
with a fairly crude algorithms and who is rapidly or very quickly noticed that was
使用相当粗糙的算法，谁能很快或非常迅速地注意到这一点，那就是
actually a bottle neck in the quality of code generation that actually limitations
实际上是代码生成质量的瓶颈，这实际上限制了
on the ability of register allocation and do a good job have a really significant
对寄存器分配能力的提高和做好寄存器分配工作有非常重要的意义
effect on the overall equality, overall quality of the code that compilers could
对编译器可以实现的代码的总体等价性、总体质量的影响
produce. And then about 30 years later, in 1980, a breakthrough occurred where people
生产。大约30年后，也就是1980年，出现了一个突破性进展，人们
discovered or a group of researchers at IBM discovered a register allocation
发现或IBM的一组研究人员发现了寄存器分配
scheme based on graph coloring. And the great thing about this scheme is that it's
基于图着色的方案。这个计划的伟大之处在于它
pretty simple. It's easy to explain. It's global, meaning it takes advantage of
很简单。这很容易解释。它是全球性的，这意味着它利用
information from the entire control flow graph at the same time and also happens to
信息同时从整个控制流程图中提取，并且碰巧
work well in practice. And here's the basic principle that underlies the modern
在实践中做好工作。这是现代社会的基本原则
register allocation algorithms. So, if I have two temporaries t1 and t2, I want to
寄存器分配算法。所以，如果我有两个临时的t1和t2，我想
know when they can share register. So, they're allowed to share a register and
知道他们何时可以共享注册表。所以，他们被允许共享一个寄存器
they're allowed to be in the same register if they are not live at the same time,
如果他们不在同一时间生活，他们就可以在同一个登记簿里，
okay? So like I said, any point in the program in most one of t1 or t2 as live.
好吧?所以就像我说的，节目中的任何一点，在T1或T2中的大多数情况下都是实时的。
And we are more concise which I already said was partially is, is that if t2, t1
我们更简洁，我已经说过，部分是，如果t2，t1
and t2 are live at the same time, okay? Meaning that there's, there's some program
和T2同时直播，好吗？意思是有，有一些程序
point were both are live then they cannot share a register, alright? So this is the
如果两个人都是现场直播的，那他们就不能共用一个录音机，好吗？所以这就是
negative form of the statement and it just tells you that if, if you need two values
语句的否定形式，它只告诉您，如果您需要两个值
at the same moment in time, then they have to be in separate registers. Let's take a
在同一时刻，那么它们必须在不同的登记簿中。让我们拿一张
look at a control flow graph and now, we know that in order to do the register allocation
看看控制流图，现在，我们知道为了进行寄存器分配
to solve the register allocation at least in this in this way, we're going to need
为了至少以这种方式解决寄存器分配问题，我们需要
liveness information. So, let's compute the live variables for each point of this
活体信息。那么，让我们计算一下每个点的活动变量
program. So, here it is and I'll just walk through it very quickly. Let's assume that
程序。所以，这就是了，我会快速浏览一下。我们假设
on exit from this loop that only b is live. So b is the output of this piece of
在从该循环退出时，只有b是活动的。所以b是这段的输出
the code and it's used elsewhere but none of the other variables are live. So, now
代码和它在其他地方使用，但是其他变量都不是活动的。那么现在
if we work backwards, remember that line is a backward analysis. We'll see here
如果我们倒着干，记住这一行是倒着分析的。我们在这里看看
that b is written so it's not live before the statement but f and c are read. So,
b被写入，所以它在语句之前不是活动的，而是f和c被读取。所以,
both c and f are live before this basic block. Okay, and similarly if we, if we go
在这个基本的挡路之前，c和f都是现场直播的。好的，同样的，如果我们，如果我们去
up another level here, here we see that e is now alive and f is dead because f was
再往上一层，这里我们看到e现在是活的，f是死的，因为
written here and e was read. And over on this path, here we have another exit where
写在这里，e被读了。在这条路上，我们还有另一个出口
b is live and now at this point here right after this basic block the set of lot
B是现场直播的，现在就在这里，在这个基本的挡路之后，一组拍品
variables that are live is b, c, and f because b is live on one path and c and f
活动的变量是b、c和f，因为b在一条路径上，而c和f在一条路径上
are live on the other path. Remember for something to be live, it only has to be
住在另一条路上。记住，要想让某件事活着，它只需要
live on some, in some future possible evolution of the execution. So, on some
活在一些，在未来的一些可能的行刑演变中。所以，在一些
path out of this node is a variables live, then it's live at the exit from this.
从这个节点出来的路径是一个活变量，那么它在这个出口处是活的。
Working backwards here. B, c, and f are live here because e is read. And b, c, and
在这里倒着工作。b、c和f驻留在这里，因为e是可读的。和b、c和
f are not referred to in this statement and so they just propagate upwards. Here b
在该语句中没有提到F，所以它们只是向上传播。这里b
is removed from the live f because it's written but d is added and set here and
从活动f中删除，因为它是写入的，但在这里添加和设置了d，并且
similarly, for the other edges in this graph. If you go and check all the other
同样，对于此图中的其他边也是如此。如果你去检查所有其他的
edges you will see that the live set is correct and it just follows from the
边，您将看到活动集是正确的，并且它只是从
simple rules we gave in the previous video. But how are going to use the
我们在上一个视频中给出了简单的规则。但是我们将如何使用
liveness information to do register allocation? Well, we're going to construct
活体信息要做寄存器分配吗？好的，我们要建造一个
and undirected graph and in this graph, there will be a node for each temporaries
和无向图，在此图中，每个时间都有一个节点
so each variable will have a node in the graph and there'll be an edge between two
因此每个变量在图中都有一个节点，在两个变量之间有一条边
temporaries if they are live simultaneously at some point in the
临时对象(如果它们同时在
program, alright? So backing up and looking at our little example here, we can
程序，好吗？所以回过头来看看我们这里的小例子，我们可以
see for example at this point in the program c and e are both live. They're
例如，在节目c和e的这一点上都是活动的。他们是
both in the live set after this basic block executes. So c and e cannot be in
两者都在这个基本的挡路执行后的现场。所以c和e不能在
the same register. Alright, continuing on, this is called, this data structure, this
同样的登记簿。好，继续，这叫这个数据结构，这个
graph is called the Register Interference Graph or RIG for short. And again, the
图形称为注册干涉图或简称为Rig。再说一遍，
basic idea is that two temporaries can be allocated in the same register if there is
基本思想是，如果存在两个临时寄存器，则可以在同一寄存器中分配两个临时寄存器
no edge connecting them in the register interference graph. So, here's a register
寄存器干涉图中没有连接它们的边。所以，这是一张收银机
interference graph for our example. This is the graph constructed from the code and
我们示例中的干涉图。这是从代码和
the line analysis that we're given a few slides ago and you know, it's easy to read
我们在几张幻灯片前看到的线条分析，你知道，它很容易读懂
off from the graph what the constraints are. So, for example b and c cannot be in
从图表中找出约束是什么。因此，例如b和c不能在
the same register because b and c are connected by an edge. Okay, seeing that
相同的寄存器，因为B和C由边缘连接。好的，看到这一点
they're live simultaneously at some part, some point in the program and so they have
他们在节目的某个部分、某个时间点同时直播，所以他们
to live in different registers. On the other hand, there is at, there is no edge
住在不同的寄存器里。从另一方面来说，就是在，没有优势。
between b and d, okay. So, this edge is missing and therefore, it's possible that
在b和d之间，好的。所以，这条边不见了，因此，有可能
b and d could be allocated in the same register. They are live ranges all the
B和D可以被分配在同一寄存器中。他们一直都是实况转播场
times in which they are alive do not overlapped. So a great thing about the
他们活着的时间并不重叠。所以有一件很棒的事，那就是
register interference graph is that it extracts exactly the information needed to
寄存器干涉图的特点是它准确地提取了所需的信息
characterize a legal register assignment. So, it gives us a representation of all
描述合法寄存器分配的特征。因此，它为我们提供了所有
the possible legal register assignments. Now, I haven't said I haven't actually get
可能的合法寄存器分配。现在，我还没有说我实际上还没有
a register assignment out of the register interference graph, but the first step is
寄存器干扰图之外的寄存器分配，但第一步是
to characterize the problem in some kind of precise way. And the graph of, cannot
以某种精确的方式描述这个问题。而图中的，不能
live in the same register constraints does that for us. The other thing that is good
居住在相同的寄存器中的约束为我们做了这件事。另一件好事是
about is a, is a global view of the register requirements meaning it's over
关于a，是注册要求的全局视图，意味着它结束了
the entire control flow graphs. So, takes into account information from every part
整个控制流程图。因此，考虑到了来自各个部分的信息
of control flow graph which will help us to make good global decisions about what
控制流图，它将帮助我们做出关于以下内容的良好的全局决策
value is very important to live in registers. And finally, the other thing to
值对于寄存器来说非常重要。最后，另一件事是
notice is that, that after reconstruction, the register allocation for algorithm is
需要注意的是，重构后，算法的寄存器分配为
going, is architecture independent. I haven't shown you the algorithm so you
去，是架构独立的。我还没给你看算法所以你
just have to believe the statement for the moment but it's going to turn out that
暂时只需要相信这一说法，但事实会证明
were not going to depend on any property of the machine except for the number of
我们不会依赖于机器的任何属性，除了
registers. So, that's the only thing we need to know about the machine in order to
寄存器。所以，这是我们唯一需要知道的关于这台机器的事情
take a RIG and, and do register allocation using it.
取一台钻机，并使用它进行寄存器分配。